This is a safe place.
What do you mean? Just
what your mum used to call it.
It's all over socials - that you killed her.
It's all your fault. and
it's being taken out on me.
What you gonna do?
Get your dad to kill me?
He'll probably get his dad to shag you.
Alana hasn't gone to her
grandparents to help them.
she's gone to get away from me.
Sarah's death is my fault.
The 24th. 25th and the 26th.
Can anyone explain where Michael was?
Alana? I don't know!
I saw Polly in a fight
with one of the boys.
"Fight". as in handbags.
like grabbing and shoving?
This wasn't just handbags. as you call it.
it was violent abuse.
Craig. listen to me. do not
come here. I am at work.
Please. Is that him?
I'll go and speak to him now.
He just gets so bloody angry. Angry?
Do yourself a favour and go back...
Take your hands off me! Agh!
Is that what you want?
Craig. please stop.
No-one's saying he did
it. that's not what I said.
but they're asking questions.
What sort of questions? Past behaviour.
Rory said he saw him in some
kind of fight on the rugby pitch.
I'm just telling you what I heard. Alana.
Let's get your stuff
and come stay with me.
Agh! Agh. agh!
Dad! Dad! Alana. wait!
I haven't done anything!
Get him inside the house.
Get him inside the house. Agh!
Dad. dad! It's all right. it's all right.
Calm down. Agh!
Ridiculous!
I have done nothing wrong!
Agh!
You should be arresting him. not me.
Charlie-X-ray-three-five-six.
can I get an eta on that back-up. please?
What the hell was that?
You had your hand
around his neck. Michael.
People are gonna think you
were trying to strangle him.
There are a few conflicting
accounts of what happened here.
What's conflicting about them?
Well. di stanhope says
that he came to see you.
Something about your
Tina Bradley review.
I actually asked him not to come.
Andy... much. who's the
sergeant on duty at the house
said it looked personal.
Not something I'm
particularly comfortable about.
given your past relationship and
given you were meant to be working.
That's exactly why I said...
And that Michael Polly
came out of the house
and tried to assault him.
That's not quite what happened.
He was forced to restrain Michael.
Yes. There's also the fact
that Michael Polly took
di stanhope by the neck.
It was more fending him off.
Sorry. who was fending who off?
Michael was fending
off Craig. di stanhope.
So. he didn't put his
hand around his neck?
It's obviously relevant. Annie. Yes.
Given how Sarah died.
It wasn't like that. Ivan.
Michael Polly is our prime
suspect in the murder of his wife.
We've spoken to di stanhope. and
he's decided not to press charges.
but. Annie. if an incident such
as this occurs during your time
as a family liaison officer.
we need to remove you from that role.
You're going to remove
me from the role?
Why? What did I do?
It's standard practice.
You need to step back. You've
compromised your position.
I thought you didn't want to be flo?
I didn't. but he's started talking.
Men like that find it hard
to talk at the best of times.
but he's started opening up to me.
Annie... You need me in there.
I even recorded some
of it. conversations.
Well. you shouldn't have...
I'll play them for you now.
I know he's not alibied.
but I don't think he's done it.
not by the way he's talking.
Let's come back to this later. No.
Let's come back to this now. ok?
I'm the only one he'll speak to.
Why won't this bloody thing open now?
Annie. we're not removing
you from the case.
There are still actions to
be carried out from here.
I don't want to work here.
Annie. you will do as you're told.
What? What was your ex doing there?
Craig?
Is that who sent you the flowers?
You said to scream at
you if you ever went back.
Why didn't you tell me?
Annie...
They want me to stop as the
flo because of what happened.
Just as he's started to talk.
they're taking it away from me.
You have no choice.
You need to tell the
police about the diary.
Your mum was scared.
That's what she wrote.
What if the victim wasn't your mum?
And the man you were
suspicious of wasn't your dad?
Would you go to the police then?
So the only thing stopping
you from telling the police
is the fact that it's your dad.
That is a thing. Paul.
Obviously. you love your dad.
but not to the point of letting him
get away with hurting your mum.
Alana. at the very least.
let the police work it out.
I don't know what it's about.
She just said she wanted
to see us after school.
Everyone's very excited about
the last game of the season.
and nobody's trying to look past
the events of the past few weeks.
Absolutely not.
The things that must have
been happening at home.
But we need to discuss
Dylan's academic work.
In English and biology.
he's just about on course.
but his history is... Well.
we're not where we need to be.
We'd like Dylan to take a
test. to assess his progress
on Monday. after school.
That's. what. three days from now?
Push him to make an improvement
in his essay writing. otherwise...
Otherwise. we're not
sure about the rugby.
about him playing in the match.
We all want him to play.
but he's way behind in terms of
his grasp of the current module.
Rugby is Dylan's best thing.
It's how he burns off energy.
It's how he expresses
himself. Why would you do that?
It's an incentive. No. it's just cruel.
Mrs Sedgwick. if Dylan doesn't improve.
he'll fall behind in terms
of his predicted grades.
university choices.
This is for him.
I've spoken to mr
whitchurch. and he agrees.
And mr Polly?
Mr Polly is currently
suspended from the school.
'Hello. you've
reached Alana Polly's phone.
'Please leave a message.
and I'll get back to you.'
Di stanhope doesn't
wish to press charges.
The incident this morning. Michael.
outside. when you accosted him.
I accosted him?
Is that how you're choosing
to remember it now. yeah?
Either way. it's not so relevant now.
as he doesn't want to press charges.
You should also know ds
Cassidy will no longer be your flo.
DC Hammond will remain in place.
and we'll find someone to replace Annie.
Who? That's all to be worked out.
And what if I don't want this person?
If it's not Annie. I don't want anyone.
In fact. I don't want anyone here.
I'm still going to update you
whenever there's a development.
You can show yourselves out.
I just wanted to check on you.
I'm worried I got a bit heavy.
I just didn't like the way he
came charging out of that house.
I told you not to come.
I said I couldn't talk.
I know. Thanks to you. I'm no longer flo.
I know. And nobody was
charging anywhere. Craig.
Look. I'm sorry if I misread it.
I just didn't want him to hurt
you. Could you listen. please?
I don't want us to mess
this up. And we won't.
Annie...
Annie... I promise you.
You've made promises before.
Please.
Please just let me book the table again
and pretend like today never happened.
Why don't you just come over.
and I'll burn you that lasagne.
like I always used to?
You'd do that for me? I'd do that for you.
Alfie lamont strangled a
woman in Leigh woods. in 2008.
He has a history of attacking
women. One of them was a jogger.
Yeah. Annie... Hang
on. Let me just finish.
Another was a Walker.
Sarah Polly was a Walker.
And then he was released
from prison. 2021. and now...
We've tried that... He
lives in abbots Leigh.
Yeah. his brother Edward
does. but Alfie lamont's in Spain.
Is he? Been there since February.
How do you know? We checked.
Just so you know.
Annie. we're doing all this.
We're looking at past offenders.
similar attacks. unsolved crimes.
While you were working as the flo.
we haven't been sat here doing nothing.
We've been working really
hard. I know how hard you work.
That bag. by the way. Ivan
says it's in the evidence room.
Bag? Bag of evidence.
It needs logging.
Stuff found at the outer
cordon of the murder site.
Ivan's asked if you could check it.
Just. you know. if you have time.
Hello? Yeah. what is it? I'm at work.
Look. it'll have to wait until I come home.
What are you doing here?
Sir. they're making me do a history test.
I'm gonna fail it... What's
this got to do with me?
You teach history.
You're my coach. sir.
If I fail the test. then my season's over.
I can't play in the final match.
Shoes.
Well. they're not wrong.
You do need to improve.
But who plays in that match. that's...
That's still my decision.
They said you were no
longer at the school. sir.
So. what's it about. this
essay? The Munich Agreement.
Mr bowman says he wants
an essay on Chamberlain.
The mistake of trusting Hitler.
Nobody wants an essay on
why it was a mistake to trust Hitler.
Isn't that what happened?
They certainly don't want an
essay just relaying what happened.
What they want is to
find out what you think.
They want an argument. An argument?
Yes. pick a line. just like in rugby.
Pick an angle. and the harder the angle.
the more impressive it is.
So. how about this -
how about that he
was right to trust Hitler?
Was he? Well. that doesn't matter.
That's what you claim.
What I'm trying to... Well.
what mr bowman is trying to do
is test your ability to make
us see history differently.
In a new way. to see it in your way.
But that's not what I'm doing
here. and you need to leave.
Please. sir.
'Our focus stays on one man.'
where was Michael
Polly in the three days
before Sarah's body was found.
before we had eyes on him at all times?
We know he left the house
on the night she went missing.
But could he have moved
the body on another night?
Seems possible.
He's got gaps in his timeline.
knowledge of his wife's affair.
a propensity for reacting physically.
Anything from the cctv and any
doorbell cameras in the area?
No. footage is patchy
because it's such a rural area.
All done?
What's he...? What's he
want me to do with these?
Just logged and bagged up properly
and taken down the evidence store.
Hello. 'Have you seen it?'
in the Mercury? The Mercury?
"Bradley family claims no
new lead in over a decade"
"as more attention is turned
to the unsolved murder"
"of a headmaster's wife."
"Brother gareth bemoans
a lack of progress."
'Talk of "well-intentioned
detectives". and...'
yeah. go on.
'And "never feeling
like Tina is the priority".
'Jesus.'
is this in today's? 'Yeah.'
after everything you've done.
We couldn't get hold of you.
Well. that's bollocks. for starters.
Where's Carol?
She's not in. She's never not in. gareth.
That's what she tells me to say
when there's someone
she doesn't wanna see.
She's got no choice. Out the way.
How did it get to this?
"Never feeling like Tina is priority"?
Carol. I'm round here every week.
I think about her every
day. She was my friend.
When did Tina go missing? What date?
You know the date.
July 17th. 2004...
Between the hours of midnight and 1am.
It's etched on my brain.
Carol. It's a long time ago.
It's getting that way.
And I love you as a friend.
But I can't help thinking. as a detective...
If you were gonna find her.
you'd have done it by now.
'What we need to remember is. for us.
'these events are historical.
'He didn't have the benefit of hindsight.'
and would we think about Chamberlain
the way that we think about
him today if we'd lost that war?
No. No. sir. So. what are we saying?
We're saying... That Chamberlain was...
"Right"? Well. we can't
use that word. but...
"Unlucky"? Yes. he was certainly that.
And maybe honourable.
because sometimes.
it's more honourable...
Not to fight.
To try and find compromise and...
A peaceful solution.
When everything is pointing
towards conflict and confrontation
and the loss again of millions of lives.
maybe the wisest or the bravest choice
is not to engage.
And that's...
An active choice in itself.
And so that can be our argument.
That's how we get
you to play in the match.
We explain the choices that
Chamberlain was facing then.
not with the benefit of hindsight.
Yes. sir. except it's...
It's not us saying it. is it?
It's... I'm writing the essay.
Yes. that's what I meant. So...
What time's the test? 5pm. Before prep.
Well. let's make some
final notes. shall we?
Dylan? Is he in there?
One of his mates said
he saw him come up here.
Dylan. out. Do you hear me?
He's helping with my history exam.
Well. he shouldn't. and he knows it.
It's totally inappropriate. Come on.
It's not inappropriate. Dylan.
Thank you. sir. Come on.
They're getting closer to proving it's Polly.
Apparently. his
mother-in-law reckons he did it.
I know you're not sure. but
even Alana's starting to wonder.
I can see it on her face.
Really? You're not talking to me now?
Annie?
Ok. If anyone asks. I've gone
to put this stuff in the store.
Ok?
Ok. Dylan. it's five
o'clock. Test starts now.
Do you want to get a coffee?
One day. I'm gonna
look back on all of this...
And I'm gonna ask myself. "did
I do the right thing for the kids?"
Saying nothing.
Doing nothing during all
this shit you've put us through.
No. I do not want to get coffee.
Come on.
Can I help you?
Sorry... Boring... routine check.
I'm looking for Edward lamont.
Edward or Eddie? If you
want Eddie. you've found him.
And if I want Edward?
I don't mind waiting.
You're gonna be waiting a while.
Dad died just before Christmas.
I'm sorry. No. don't be.
All these women came out
the woodwork. all this other stuff.
In. in! Shh. shh! In. in!
You spend all your time
thinking you know a guy.
taking his word for things.
turns out he's capable of all sorts.
Do you. wanna see
the death certificate? No.
I don't mind. if it helps you with... sorry.
In! Go. go.
Before we tell you what we think.
I want to say well done to you.
Mr bowman showed me your essay.
and it's clear you did a lot
of reading on the subject.
so we first want to
commend you on that.
What do you say? Thank you.
He put a lot of work in. didn't you. mate?
It's very important to
him. playing in the rugby.
And getting better at
history. Yeah. absolutely.
That's the point of this.
We both took a look at your essay.
and there was a lot of great work in it.
but neither of us felt that we saw
the improvement that we were after.
Chamberlain hesitated.
But I'm saying the opposite.
Failed to stand up.
But what I'm saying is
that he didn't want a war
in a "far away country".
Exactly. We went through that in class.
A man who fails to address his problems.
You try and make the
argument that it's honourable.
It's probably easier to argue
that it's weak or cowardly.
So does this mean I
can't play in the match?
25 grand a fucking year. and for what?
Fuck off!
After what you've
done to her?! My mum!
Stop it! This isn't about me!
It's not about me!
They're not punishing me!
You don't... you don't get it.
Ok. they're punishing you!
I'm angry because of you!
Dylan...
Come on.
'Back on 74' by jungle.
Annie!
Annie! Open the door!
Annie. it's me! I'm at
the door! Craig. sor...
Sorry. sorry. I was
getting a bit carried away.
There you are.
Left me standing around here
like some sort of fucking idiot.
Jesus Christ!
Open the fucking door.
Annie... open the door.
Fuck it. I'll use my own key. then.
Fuck. fuck!
You can't go locking me out of
my own fucking house. Annie.
Jesus Christ.
What are you gonna do. feed
me through the fucking letterbox?
Fucking hell.
I don't know.
I thought you'd moved
beyond all this. all these games.
Annie. I have the forensics
report for the handbag.
Do you wanna see it or not?
Hello! I know you can see me.
I'm doing everything
right here. To the letter.
This is bullshit.
Fuck this.
Is that your plan - to get me to
shout at you on door camera?
I know you're there.
Look. there's the forensic report.
I was so looking forward
to bringing it to you.
- Now look what you're making me do.
- Breaking into my own fucking house!
I love you.
Remember? I love you.
I hate it when you make us fight like this.
It triggers me. You know it
does. Why would you do that?
No wonder they ended
up going to the papers.
She'll talk to you.
But not in the house.
Paul says I need to go to the police.
Says... some of that stuff in mum's diary
is stuff they need to be aware of.
But before we go. dad. I
need to ask you a question.
I need you to turn around
and look me in the eye so
I can ask you the question.
And I need you to tell me the truth.
Turn around.
Dad?
Did you kill mum?
Couldn't you have just let her go?
I'm sorry. sir. but they didn't want it.
They didn't want what you had to say.
Sorry. what does that mean?
Well. they didn't like my essay.
They didn't like the
fact that I came to you
and I asked you for help.
And you couldn't. You didn't teach me.
Y-You messed it up.
Dylan. I'm sorry you feel
like that. but that's not...
You were teaching me for yourself.
You were thinking of yourself
when you were talking to me.
Your best player. and
you still... You fuck it up!
Don't use that word! Why?
You gonna take it out on me again?
What your wife did with my
dad. that's your fault. it's not mine!
You wouldn't pick yourself. sir.
Because you're a pussy.
Don't use that word. You're a pussy!
Just watch your mouth.
No. sir! You watch my mouth!
You don't fight.
You give everyone this speech
about how everyone should
"have each other's backs".
yet you don't do shit for anyone!
No wonder people are pointing fingers.
No wonder everyone's gone.
What are you gonna do about it?
Go on. sir. W-What are
you gonna do to fix it?
That's what I thought.
I'm sorry.
If he makes you happy.
who am I to judge?
I'm gonna back off.
Guv? Guv. the daughter's here.
Wants to give us a new statement. Here.
'Hello. you've
reached Alana Polly's phone.
'Please leave a message.
and I'll get back to you.'
I wanna tell you everything.
but I want Paul to stay.
Alana. this is all on your terms.
There'd been a lot of fighting
between mum and dad.
That's the first thing.
In the evenings.
er. one time after they
thought I was teaching.
but I was still in the house.
She was scared of him.
'You think she was
scared?' 'I know she was.'
she told you?
She wrote it in her diary.
We had mum's diary. I...
I took the pages out
because they were private.
And where are those pages now?
They burned them. her and Michael.
She's worried that she's
gonna get in trouble for that.
but I've said that she shouldn't be.
It's best to tell you everything.
That's right. Alana...
Alana. as long as you tell us the truth.
you've nothing to be worried about. ok?
She was scared of
him. That's what it said.
And I've been thinking
about it ever since.
How... I've lived with him all this time.
that he loves me.
But I don't really know him.
'You know. what he feels.'
what he felt about your mum?
And what he feels about
you? About anything.
They don't... do they?
Men like that. they tell
you the practical stuff.
but they never let you in.
They can't.
Then we went to see him
this morning. didn't we?
Yeah. I wanted to ask him...
To his face.
If he killed your mum?
You asked him that?
He didn't say anything.
Subtitles by accessibility@itv.Com